Reversing diabetes is a term that usually refers to a significant long-term
improvement in insulin sensitivity in people with type 2 diabetes. People with
type 2 diabetes that are able to get their HbA1c below 42 millimoles per mole
or 6% without taking diabetes medication are said to have reversed or resolved
their diabetes. So how can you have skinny people with type 2 diabetes and
this is something that's often called TOFI or TOFI which is thin on the
outside fat on the inside. Do you want to learn more about the insulin resistance
diet because you think you're insulin resistant? Well you're in the right place.
Insulin resistance affects a large proportion of American population and
the rest of the world too. So its presence often goes unnoticed and unchecked for a
long time. In adults insulin resistance can progress to pre-diabetes and if left
untreated. We divide it into two types of fat subcutaneous fat which is under the
skin and visceral fat which is the fat that is concentrated really around the
midsection.